Guide to the Elliott Crayton McCants Papers, 1886-1950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Elliott Crayton McCants papers 1886-1950
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
McCants, Elliott Crayton, 1865-1953
2.5 linear feet Extent: 163 Items
Superintendent of schools in Anderson, S.C.; author. The collection contains largely correspondence concerning the publication of McCants' writings.
RL.00864
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Elliott Crayton McCants Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift and deposit in 1956-1957.
Biographical Note
Elliott Crayton McCants was superintendent of schools in Anderson, SC and an author.
Collection Overview
Chiefly correspondence by E.C. McCants concerning the publication of his writings. Some letters refer to school issues. Also includes contracts for published books, copies of his writings, clippings, and a program of a banquet given in 1940 in honor of E.C. McCants. His field of writing most often concerned South Carolina history and legends.
Subject Headings
Education -- South Carolina; Publishers and publishing -- United States; South Carolina -- History; Anderson (S.C.); Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Correspondence, 1908-1945 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1950, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, various dates (Box 1)
  - Notes, various dates and undated (Box 1)
  - Works, undated (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Works, undated (Box 2)
  - Ann Jeremiah's Seventh Husband, undated (Box 2)
  - Aristocrat, The Ultimate Argument, Aristocracy, Simplicity, and One Talent or None?, undated (Box 2)
  - Cateeche, undated (Box 2)
  - Osceola, the Seminole and Cateeche II, undated (Box 2)
  - A Colonial Romance, undated (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, undated (Box 2)
  - Kate Fowler, undated (Box 2)
  - Works, undated (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Reminiscences and Remarks, undated (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - Works, undated (4 folders) (Box 3)
  - The Facts in the Case, undated (Box 4)
  - The Fool of Feringhistan, undated (Box 4)
  - Imports from Madagascar, undated (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Kate Fowler, undated (Box 4)
  - Biographical Sketch, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Letters, various dates (Box 5)
  - The Shakespeare Birthday Book, 1886 (Box 5)
  - Year Book, 1934 (Box 5)
  - Year Book, 1937 (Box 5)
  - One Long Trail, undated (Box 5)
  - Teachers' Manual: Boys' High School, 1944-1945 (Box 5)
  - The Seed of Rice, undated (Box 5)
  - Osceola, the Seminole, undated (Box 5)
  - Pocket Book, 1925 (Box 5)
  - Memo Book, undated (Box 5)